Sub by ®VIU
The Good Detective - JTBC
Synced by ParkMinYoung℠
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS, RELIGIONS, ORGANIZATIONS,
AND INCIDENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS.
EPISODE 4
JO SEONG DAE, SERVED 4 YEARS FOR ASSAULT AND THEFT
This looks like the guy, right?
Someone sent me Lee Dae Chul's CCTV footage via e-mail.
The detective who was in charge of the case also received it.
Had that evidence been submitted at his trial four years ago,
the verdict would've been different.
Right.
All eyes were on the Lee Dae Chul's case back then,
and it was a game the prosecution had to win no matter what.
The evidence was going to put them at a disadvantage,
so they obviously didn't want to dig their own grave.
Right.
Then why...
Why reveal it now?
That person...
is ruining his career he's built over the years with his own hands.
I'm not so sure about that.
Because an innocent person is about to be executed?
Because of guilt?
Your recent article...
about the families of the victims murdered by the death-row convict.
Was that your idea?
Someone put you up to it, right?
The media is only talking about Jo Byeong Gil.
People don't even know that Lee Dae Chul will be executed.
The person who made you write that article.
What that person wanted wasn't...
executing serial killers like Jo Byeong Gil.
What that person wanted was...
Lee Dae Chul.
Do you know how you can cover up a case most effectively?
Making the victim disappear...
forever.
Gone.
Your recent article...
about the families of the victims murdered by the death-row convict.
Someone put you up to it, right?
It's still off the record.
Let's cover this before it comes out in the open.
I'd like you to interview the victims' families.
Would you like to be dropped off where I picked you up?
Yes.
Excuse me.
How do you know the Chief Prosecutor?
It doesn't seem like you work in the prosecution.
I'm just someone who has big respect for him.
He was in jail in the Philippines for robbery and murder.
And he was named as the suspect in many cases even after returning.
I bet he killed Park Gun Ho.
The problem is, how Park Gun Ho found out about the real culprit.
We must solve that...
to prove how these are linked.
But the thing is, Park Gun Ho is dead now.
It's likely that he told someone before he died.
Who?
Lee Eun Hye.
What does she have? Is it a serious condition?
She has epilepsy.
It's a chronic condition...
but not serious enough to require hospitalization.
Then why is she hospitalized?
Just in case.
Once Park Gun Ho is gone, as he did in our case,
she would become the only person...
who may know what he was really thinking.
I bet many have told you that they think you're obnoxious.
How would I know? It's not like people will say that to my face.
You are obnoxious.
So obnoxious.
How are you feeling?
I heard you haven't been eating the hospital food.
Is there anything you want to eat? I'll pick it up for you.
Park Gun Ho has been murdered.
Did he say anything to you about the real culprit?
You obviously cooperated and did what he told you to do...
because there was a valid reason.
Park Gun Ho was on your father's side.
We should find out who killed him, shouldn't we?
- What's going on?
- What's happening?
- Is she okay?
- Please don't worry. It's nothing.
- What's wrong?
- She's a patient.
Get back to your own business.
She's a patient. Are you guys that curious?
I guess it's nothing serious.
Peek in if you're curious. I told you that she's a patient.
- I see.
- Is she okay?
Let's wait until she calms down...
and try to talk to her again.
Forget it. Just wait in the car.
You can't persuade that girl by being nice to her.
Do you want to see her foam at the mouth and pass out again?
You may not remember this,
but I was the one...
who arrested your father five years ago.
Do you happen to remember...
the bag of tangerines left on your kitchen table for days...
five years ago?
When I was transferring your father...
to the prosecution after getting his statement,
he stopped...
and asked me for a favor.
He said, "My daughter, Eun Hye,"
"plays video games for an hour after school,"
"and that's the only thing that gives her joy." He also said...
you always eat tangerines when you do that.
He was worried you'd throw them out if I told you they were from him,
so he asked me...
to just leave them on the kitchen table.
At the time,
I was 100 percent convinced that your father was the culprit.
But at that moment...
In that split second,
I thought to myself that he may not be the culprit.
And I plan to...
I plan to reinvestigate the case...
and find out...
why that keeps bothering me.
Eun Hye.
Your father...
will be executed soon.
Did you get anything out of Eun Hye?
What did she say?
Lee Dae Chul asked Park Gun Ho for a favor.
I'm glad.
You now know the truth.
What?
What do I know?
I'll die anyway even if I'm left alone.
So why...
Why do you think he tried to kill me ahead of that?
It means someone wants me dead soon.
Let's make a deal.
What happened between us...
I'll take it to the grave.
Please talk to my daughter Eun Hye in exchange.
Tell her that her father didn't murder anyone.
Please, Officer Park.
Officer Park...
Is she your daughter?
Yes.
Where is she now?
I haven't seen her ever since I was arrested.
She's abandoned you. I don't think she'd believe me even if I met her.
She's my only treasure...
and the only reason for living.
Eun Hye knows that.
She's a very sweet girl.
She will trust her dad.
Run!
Eun Hye...
believes her dad's innocence.
She has to since it's her dad.
Finally, the reason...
Park Gun Ho had to die can be explained.
I'll send you the name and address.
I already have his criminal record,
but I want to know what Jo Seong Dae has been up to, what he does,
and where he is usually seen.
It's okay if it takes time. Please look into it.
Yes, thank you.
Why are you suddenly drinking at home?
We aren't here to drink,
but didn't have anywhere else to talk.
I'm on leave so can't go to the station...
and I wanted you to meet my new partner.
Hello.
Why did you become a detective...
when you're so handsome?
Many detectives nowadays...
look better than I do.
That's why I'm asking. I'd like to ask all of them.
Detectives should look beat up like him.
Stop being ridiculous and leave us. We need to discuss something.
Don't drink too much. I bought it for myself.
Leave us already.
I can smell alcohol on your breath. It's embarrassing,
so go inside, please.
You crazy...
Has she lost her mind?
- Keep it to a bottle.
- Okay.
- Would you like a drink?
- No, I drove.
Do you remember when...
Park Gun Ho faked a seizure in the holding cell?
He knew of Eun Hye's illness.
He wanted to tell us...
that we made Eun Hye sick.
Why do you think Park Gun Ho is right?
I don't think he's right,
but I think I know...
why he thought Lee Dae Chul is innocent.
Then...
do you think Lee Dae Chul is innocent?
Your opinion is more important than mine.
What do you think?
I thought Lee Dae Chul was guilty until now,
but from now on I'm going to forget about that thought.
I'm going back to when I first faced the case.
Lee Dae Chul is neither guilty nor innocent.
What if Lee Dae Chul's innocence is proved?
Then we'll have to save him.
The person who made you write that article.
What that person wanted wasn't...
executing serial killers like Jo Byeong Gil.
What that person wanted was...
Lee Dae Chul.
Mr. Yoo.
Oh, you're here.
Is something weighing you down?
Would you like some tea?
Is something up?
- Let's have a seat.
- Okay.
Is it bad?
Reporter Jin.
I think I'll be able to keep the promise I made you.
You start working here tomorrow. The director approved of it.
The team here can be territorial.
Yes, I've prepared myself for that.
Then why did you look so down?
You don't have to come if you're comfortable where you are.
Are you kidding me?
Are you trying to tease me?
Fine, let's be a good team.
Okay.
Shouldn't I buy you a drink? I also have something to tell you.
I have plans...
Okay, next time then.
No, you can come with me.
Aren't you being harassed nowadays?
Excuse me?
Those against the death penalty...
must have ripped you apart.
Reporters should take that as something normal.
Anyway, thank you.
Excuse me?
The current government promised to abolish the death penalty.
They will be keeping that promise sooner or later.
The problem is the prisoners on death row.
They may have to let a murderer...
that killed 11 people live.
In order to abolish the death penalty,
we needed to execute the death-row convicts.
We had to have the people know that it is the right thing to do.
That's why you needed my article.
I'll be honest with you.
I'll probably become the next Minister of Justice.
The death penalty will be abolished during my term.
Before I take office,
I needed to get rid of anything...
that would cause a political problem for me.
You should be the one buying me a drink.
I understand. Family comes first.
Thank you for understanding.
However,
couldn't you have hidden your intentions to the end?
You'd find out even if I tried to hide it.
I told you before you caught on.
I know this is out of the blue, but...
Isn't that the real question you had for me?
Is there...
something between you and Chief Prosecutor Kim...
that I don't know about?
There's something between him and my brother, not me.
They were rivals since they were in school.
They both think they have to bring the other one down...
to be able to become successful.
It's the relationship they have.
Would you like another drink?
No, it's my first day at the head office.
I can't show up with a drunk, puffy face.
All right. See you at the office tomorrow.
Wait.
Is my job at the head office...
a personal gift from you?
We...
aren't close enough to give each other gifts.
Of course.
See you tomorrow!
Hello, come in.
SEOBU POLICE STATION
Superintendent Moon wants to see me.
I'm sure he'll throw a fit about us being drunk on the job.
He might want to talk to you too,
so let's get our stories straight.
We don't have to tell every detail about...
why we were drinking to the superintendent.
I am going to tell them the truth.
Hey!
Detective Kang didn't give up on this case.
I'm going to follow Detective Kang with confidence.
Gosh...
Jae Hong, we are going to get scorned at this rate.
We all might get replaced.
Okay. I get it.
Just go talk to the superintendent.
I am counting on you.
Good luck, sir.
Hey, Shim Dong Wook
- Yes?
- I am warning you.
Just because others are being sassy to Chief, doesn't mean you can too.
You are not in a position to do so.
Hey, Kwon Jae Hong.
When I checked with the patrol,
they said Kang Do Chang and Oh Ji Hyuk were aware of...
a possible case when they arrived at the site.
Were they in touch with Park Gun Ho all this time?
Well, I don't think so.
Other than that, the situation doesn't match up.
I just remembered something.
This is a secret but...
Do Chang...
saw Park Gun Ho getting murdered at that very site...
in his dream.
What are you doing to Chief?
Chief, if you like to know who the culprit of this case is,
call Do Chang.
He just got possessed by a spirit,
so he is very skilled in that sense.
I believe he can tell the future.
Do Chang, you don't look like someone on vacation.
Smile.
Okay.
Ready? 1,2,3.
I understand why detectives drink while working.
When I was doing the fieldwork,
I got called to sites while I was drinking at night.
That doesn't mean that I don't understand Chief Nam Guk Hyun.
He should be like that as a chief.
Furthermore, it is a murder scene.
The problem is the fact that you got caught.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Either way,
if that continuously gets mentioned by Chief Nam Guk Hyun,
I can't keep it quiet as a superintendent.
Do you understand the position that I'm in right now?
Yes.
For now, there won't be any disciplinary punishment.
If you get punished for something like this,
this will make it difficult to control all the detectives.
However, your team needs to help out Chief Nam...
in investigating Park Gun Ho.
That way, Chief Nam will not make a big deal out of it.
Yes, of course.
By the way, I heard that Kang Do Chang was at the scene too.
Did he not tell you that I sent him on vacation?
No, he told me about it.
Is he still attached to Lee Dae Chul's case?
No, that is not it.
Then why does a person on vacation show up at the crime scene?
I told him to take a break but why isn't he taking one?
About that...
Excuse me, sir.
ON VACATION NOW. I'M SORRY THAT I AM HAVING FUN BY MYSELF.
KANG DO CHANG
Kang Do Chang is having fun right now.
- That is a lot of fish.
- Right?
- Have fun fishing.
- Thank you.
I can't believe this.
I'm even fabricating an alibi when I am a detective.
Thank you for your help.
Jo Seong Dae has an office in Ansan, Gyeonggi-do.
He runs a company under his own name?
I guess he does have the guts.
We might catch him sooner than we thought.
I think it won't be easy.
If he is exposing that much about himself,
he must be confident enough...
to not get caught.
SOMEONE ELSE'S SISTER IN THE NEXT LIFE
What now? What is it this time?
I want to kill myself.
Should I really kill myself?
Where are you now?
I am at the police station.
Were you drinking and causing trouble in the daylight again?
That jerk!
That jerk filed a restraining order against me.
I went to see Jae Woong, and I got arrested by the police.
A mother went to see her own son...
and got arrested by the police.
Is it illegal to go to see my own son?
Is that what the law states?
Say something!
Say something! You haughty Korean police officer!
You should come with me.
I think I might end up killing a person right now.
Let's go.
Who is it?
Is that you, Jae Woong?
It's me, your uncle. Detective uncle.
Jae Woong, look at your face.
Have you been going to school?
Have you been eating well?
What happened to your face? Why do you look so haggard?
Do you miss your mom?
Where is dad?
He is not here.
That jerk. He made a little kid a liar.
Jae Woong.
You remember your favorite tteokbokki place, right?
Go and eat tteokbokki, fish cake, and whatever you want.
And after that, go hang out in the playground.
Go on. Come back when you're done.
You jerk! I am going to kill you!
Excuse me.
Can I get a cup of water?
I am a co-worker who works with Detective Kang.
I am sorry.
I am really sorry.
Honestly, isn't it too harsh to file a restraining order...
against the child's mother?
Do Chang, this is the only way she will pull it together.
But she is the child's mother.
It is normal for a mother to want to see her own son.
I am begging you.
Please tell her to stop interfering with my life.
She is so annoying!
She is an obstacle in my life. A really big obstacle.
Still...
She used to live with you under the same roof.
Exactly.
Since I lived with her under the same roof,
shouldn't you be thanking me for it?
I'm sorry.
I will clean it up.
Where is the broom?
Gosh...
I found a rag.
I understand that you hate her,
and that is why you divorced her.
But is there a particular reason you need to live with Jae Woong?
Wouldn't it be better if you leave Jae Woong with his mom...
and you live your own life?
You think I don't know that?
Also, what money does she have to take care of Jae Woong?
I can...
I can take care of them.
I have the capability to do so.
Are you sure?
Darn it.
Hey...
Why don't you just take a look at this?
The court sent it to me a while ago.
It says that they are going to investigate my bank statement.
Because you are under investigation for corruption.
INCHEON DISTRICT COURT
Looking at this, how could I...
trust anybody to take care of my son?
That's enough.
Do Chang.
Ji Hyuk.
I have to go somewhere.
So you should investigate...
about Jo Seong Dae's whereabouts.
Okay.
INCHEON METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
CIVIL PETITION DIVISION
Yoon Sang Mi!
You are such a jerk!
How could you do this to me?
How could you be so cold-hearted?
- How dare you?
- Come with me.
PARKING LOT, DAEHAN CLINIC
DONGCHEON MONKFISH
MECCA 7 GAME LAND
We'll be in touch.
Okay, thank you.
Excuse me. Is the owner here at the moment?
Well...
Can I help you?
Hello, I'm here to see the owner.
Why do you need to see my boss?
I'd like to speak with him in person.
He's abroad at the moment.
What are you talking about? I saw him yesterday.
Jo Seong Dae is inside, right?
You'd better get out while I'm still being nice to you.
You see,
I have to see him today.
Do you know how much money he borrowed from me and ran off?
I'm giving you the last chance to walk out of here on your own.
One.
Two.
Three.
Who is that jerk?
Hey. Darn it. Get out of there.
Unlock the door!
Hey, who are you?
WE ARE HIRING.
CEO JO SEONG DAE
KIM GI TAE, PROSECUTION SERVICE
Do you have a death wish?
What should we start with?
First, I'll break those rude fingers of yours.
Whack him!
You little...
Kill him!
I got him.
Whack him!
How dare you.
Hey, quick.
- Hey, just kill him.
- Gosh.
You scumbag!
Excuse me, please don't tell your boss about this.
Those guys will get fired for not doing their job.
Hey, get this off me.
Get this off me, please.
I can't believe...
you even went through my brother-in-law's bank account.
Checking family members' accounts is part of the normal procedure.
My sister is actually divorced now, so that jerk is no longer my family.
You didn't even do that much research?
I have confirmed that they're now divorced.
However, the alleged corruption...
took place before they got a divorce.
My sister is in...
a child custody battle with her ex-husband at the moment.
She has nothing.
The only person she can rely on is me, who also has nothing.
She was already losing the custody battle over my nephew,
and you basically gave her ex-husband a knife to slay her.
Do you realize what you have done?
I was simply drawing the line between work and personal matters.
You see,
when you feel pressured, threatened,
and cornered,
you can't help but doubt people.
"Why did that happen to that person at that specific timing?"
"Back then, I thought it was just a coincidence."
"How come I now feel as though I can see that person's intentions?"
I'll probably have to turn my back on a junior officer I'm close to...
so that I, too, can keep personal matters separate from work.
Why does this sound like a threat to me?
You see, only those who are holding the knife can make threats.
Had I been afraid of those with a knife,
I would've left the force a long time ago.
SEOBU DETENTION HOUSE
MINISTRY OF JUSTICE
CHIEF PROSECUTOR KIM GI TAE
SEOBU DETENTION HOUSE
Hello, Detective Oh.
Hi. I came to meet with Kim Gi Tae, the former chief prosecutor.
The former chief prosecutor, Kim Gi Tae?
Why?
Park Gun Ho's phone has been retrieved.
What?
Like Park Gun Ho had said, there were some photos on the phone.
We identified the person in the photos.
It's a man named Jo Seong Dae.
Jo Seong Dae?
I found Kim Gi Tae's business card on his desk,
so those two must be connected.
I called you because I was wondering...
if you met Jo Seong Dae or heard anything about him...
while investigating Kim Gi Tae.
Not that I recall.
I've never heard of such a name.
All right. I'll send you a photo of him. Please let me know.
Okay.
I'm on my way to the detention house as well,
so let's talk there.
All right, I'll wait for you.
I heard...
you reached out to Mr. Kim this time saying you'd like to speak with him.
Correct.
What is it regarding?
There's something I need to check.
DETECTIVE OH JI HYUK
Reporter Jin.
Yes?
You're not wearing your seat belt.
- Oh, right.
- They even check the back seat now.
Put on the seat belt, please.
Okay.
You've gone off route. Recalculating the route.
- Why...
- You see,
it zones out like that from time to time.
Don't worry.
I definitely know my way around from here on.
I'm sorry,
but can we stop by that gas station for a moment?
I really need to use the washroom.
Can you hold it?
We're almost there.
I really need to go. Please.
Why do I suddenly have an upset stomach?
All right, then.
SIMBOK GAS STATION
The washroom is over there. Gosh, my stomach...
WASHROOM
Hey.
The office?
Who?
I'm with the man in that photo.
Yes, that's right. The man named Jo Seong Dae.
Please hurry.
Where am I now?
It's a gas station.
I forgot to check the name because I was too flustered.
What?
Okay.
I'll check the location and send it to you.
Please hurry.
Gosh, why isn't this getting a signal?
There.
SIMBOK GAS STATION
DETECTIVE OH JI HYUK
Please don't kill me.
Whom did you call?
It's just...
someone from work.
DETECTIVE OH JI HYUK
Detective Oh Ji Hyuk.
POWER OFF
Let's get going now.
WASHROOM
SIMBOK GAS STATION
Reporter Jin.
Forget about...
- what just went through your mind.
- I'm a reporter,
a reporter with Junghan Daily.
It'll be tough to clean up if anything happens to me.
We ran out of time.
The hours are designated for special visits.
You should get in the habit of wearing a seatbelt.
Seriously?
What's going on, Mister?
What's that?
- Are you okay?
- No, I'm not.
- What's this?
- A suspect.
- For what?
- We're still investigating it.
I'll tell you when it's over.
EVIDENCE
Did you kill Park Gun Ho with this knife?
This isn't a knife you use on people.
You threatened a reporter with it.
She said she was locked in the bathroom,
so I just used it to open the lock.
- What else?
- Starting today,
we'll count the days.
Once I get a hold of something, I never let go.
Not until the target is in a prisoner's uniform.
That knife.
You'll give it back when the investigation is over, right?
I'm quite attached to it.
I'm sure he's a murderer.
I've never sensed such a violent temper in my life.
I'm not biased because he killed Park Gun Ho.
I really...
thought I might die there.
All right. Go home and get some rest.
I'll call you later if I need you to testify.
Thank you.
You did the right thing to call patrol cars.
But it was reckless of you...
to block a speeding car,
although you saved my life by doing so.
I was going to shoot the gun.
I would have if he came any closer.
I was in the car too.
Didn't you think you could've hurt me?
If you shoot the driver,
the car could overturn...
or hit another car.
Come to think about it,
you're right.
What did you just say?
The briefing for Park Gun Ho's case is starting now.
At approximately 4pm on November 28,
Park Gun Ho was found dead at Haehwa Apartment in Incheon.
SEOBU POLICE STATION
We have come to the conclusion...
that Park Gun Ho committed suicide, jumping to his death.
Do you know why he committed suicide?
Was there a will?
No, there was no will.
However, we believe that the fear of...
having to do prison time for what he recently did...
was the reason he committed suicide.
He was booked without detention.
Why would he have felt pressured in that situation?
Park Gun Ho used to be a correctional officer.
He must have been terrified of...
being locked up with prisoners he used to supervise.
Does the coroner that performed the autopsy agree with you?
There was a cut on his thigh.
However, his body was found in a deserted apartment.
The coroner mentioned the cut could have occurred...
from some kind of metal during his fall.
Who performed the autopsy?
Why do you think Park Gun Ho was at the deserted apartment?
I've never seen such a forced investigation.
He is determined to cover up the case.
Is it okay for the police to do this?
What will happen to Jo Seong Dae?
If the case is closed as a suicide,
Jo Seong Dae won't be a suspect anymore.
We'll have to let him go.
Think about what he did to me.
You can't let him go like that.
All we have on him is threatening.
He could have killed me.
You don't know what he'll do to me.
Reporters are similar to detectives, aren't they?
You should quit your job if you can't take that risk.
Reporters don't have guns, but detectives do!
You look disappointed.
Gosh, I am too.
If it were a murder case like you said,
it was a good opportunity to score extra points.
Even if the higher-ups gave him an order,
don't you think he's going too far?
I have a feeling he's closely related to...
the case from five years ago.
He was the detective in charge of Lee Dae Chul's case...
and the partner of Detective Jang Jin Soo, who got killed.
Those two were partners?
I'm at home. I took a little nap.
I know that place. I'll take a taxi.
I'll arrive in about 30 minutes.
After getting drunk and throwing a tantrum last night,
how can you drink from the morning?
Can't you put that jerk behind bars?
You're a cop.
I can't unless he's guilty.
Just make something up and arrest him.
Other cops do that all the time. Why can't you?
Do you think that makes sense?
I just talked to him on the phone.
They checked his bank accounts while doing a background check on you.
That's why he got mad and did that to me.
I didn't do anything wrong. It just happened that way.
You must have done something to make them do a check on you.
So why can't you arrest that jerk already?
Can't a cop do that much for his little sister?
Just drink.
Leave me alone. I didn't do anything wrong.
What about me?
I can't see Jae Woong for the rest of my life?
I miss him.
I want to touch him.
It's driving me crazy, Do Chang.
Please.
That's the only way I can think of.
I'm sorry.
But I can't do that.
A cop shouldn't do that.
Never.
Isn't that strange?
He's going out with his dead partner's wife?
Maybe they got close while he was trying to comfort her.
I doubt Detective Oh would have such a naive view on the matter.
Detective Jang pursued Lee Dae Chul...
even though he had an alibi.
He must have been bought off by someone.
It's highly likely that his partner, Nam Guk Hyun, was in it too.
Those two must have shared something with each other...
instead of her dead husband.
What's the matter?
Search everywhere.
They're searching your desk and everything.
Did you do something to upset the higher-ups again?
Hey, stop!
You said you'd only search Kang Do Chang's desk.
Stay away from the others' desks!
We're only following the orders.
- What are you doing?
- They're searching...
everyone's desk now!
They're all clean. It'll be fine.
What if they find something even if it's something trivial?
Fine.
Whatever they find, I'll take responsibility for it. Don't worry.
All right.
That sly jerk.
What's wrong?
Fine, bring it on.
I'll get to the bottom of things by all means.
You little rat.
PROJECT REPORT
Don't let it bother you.
It's fine as long as we have nothing to hide.
It's just that I feel humiliated.
Why are they only going after us? Let's face it,
everyone knows those jerks take bribes all the time.
Why check us out...
while leaving them alone? Why?
It was all just for show.
Otherwise, why would they take a whole hour?
It could have been done in ten minutes.
They wanted everyone to see it.
They wanted to humiliate us.
It was all just for show. Don't worry.
Chief, something smells fishy.
Why would they do this while Do Chang is on vacation?
The way they treated Park Gun Ho's case was ridiculous too.
Could they have done this to stop us from questioning...
Park Gun Ho's case?
Gosh, you're delusional.
You idiots.
Do you think what you're doing is so important?
In the higher-ups' eyes, you're mere minnows.
Why would they even care about us? They just...
did it. For no reason.
And we were just unlucky.
Stop overthinking. Know your place, you fools.
Hey, there's no need to put ourselves down.
All we have to do is have a drink...
and forget everything.
That's how we roll, right?
Let's go. The drinks are on me.
Forget it. I'm going home.
Are you sure?
Then should we go without him?
Why couldn't he just let it lie?
It's not like he can handle everything himself.
Why does he have to cause everyone trouble?
Gosh, this is frustrating.
Be careful not to drink too much.
Don't you dare make a scene again.
- Let me pour you one.
- Chief.
I know I'm inexperienced,
but isn't the situation...
just too obvious?
They treated Park Gun Ho's case in such an absurd way...
because they don't want Lee Dae Chul's case to be reinvestigated.
Like Kwon Jae Hong said,
there's no need to overthink it.
Just drink and forget it. That's why I'm buying you drinks.
So let's just drink.
I don't agree...
that we're mere minnows.
They can treat us this way...
because we don't stand up to their unreasonable behavior.
We may not be able to change the whole world,
but I believe we can still change one person's life.
Gosh, I think those girls are interested in me.
My goodness.
They're interested in me, not you.
I... I like the girl on the right.
But they're too young.
Go over and talk to them or something.
It's too early.
They should drink some more.
Once they get drunk...
What are you two doing now?
- What?
- You really want to hit on girls?
Think about our situation.
Forget it. You guys continue being oblivious.
What would I say to you?
You wouldn't pay attention anyway.
What's with him?
Drink. Drink up.
Does he think this is only hard for him?
MEETING PLACE: INDOOR FOOD STALL
Hey.
Do you think I don't know this is unreasonable?
It's the same with Man Gu and Ji Woong.
They know it too,
but they're just putting up with it.
At first, I thought...
all police officers were fighters for justice.
But this is just another society.
Some are mean,
some deceive others to get ahead of them,
and some are just downright selfish.
And some are stupid like Kang Do Chang.
"As cops, we can't do this."
There's no such thing.
Don't hold cops to such high standards.
We're...
only human, after all.
MEETING PLACE: INDOOR FOOD STALL
We just do what we're told to do.
This is where Park Gun Ho first made a report to you, right?
Yes.
Now I get it.
Park Gun Ho wanted to tell us...
that this is where...
we must start over.
Leading up to Ms. Yoon Ji Sun's death,
did anything suspicious happen?
Why are you asking about that out of the blue?
We need to gather supplementary information.
I'm sorry to ask you to do this, but please try to remember.
I'm not sure.
Did she have a boyfriend?
Or a guy who chased after her, for example.
She did have a boyfriend.
I do recall overhearing them having an argument over the phone.
But other than that, I don't really recall anything.
Do you know who her boyfriend was?
Wasn't this covered in the original investigation?
Why ask her about those things again?
No, we didn't cover this back then.
Investigating the people around the victim is...
one of the first things you must do.
How come?
Has Lee Dae Chul confessed?
Hello, sir.
I don't think it'll be easy to get his confession.
How come? We have all the evidence.
I can't stop thinking that...
we don't have enough information on the people around Yoon Ji Sun.
I should meet them again and...
This case is...
all over the media at the moment.
They're praising us for catching the killer quickly.
If we let this drag on,
they'll question everything about the investigation.
I mean, we already have the culprit.
Why create a situation where we may get blamed?
You and Jang Jin Soo joined the force in the same year, right?
- Yes, sir.
- He killed one of us.
If we give a scumbag like him...
time to get out of this,
both of us will have to give up our police badges, don't you think?
Right?
You jerk. You scumbag!
I'd crush your skull right now if I could, you scumbag.
I... I didn't kill her.
I really didn't kill that female college student.
I mean, why would I kill her?
We found your fingerprint as well as your blood...
on the weapon that killed Detective Jang Jin Soo.
If you didn't kill Yoon Ji Sun,
then why did you kill Detective Jang Jin Soo?
You obviously killed him...
to cover up the murder, you jerk!
You lunatic!
That hurts! No!
Please... I didn't...
So no one investigated Yoon Ji Sun's boyfriend at the time.
Before Yoon Ji Sun died,
she shared her studio with a classmate.
That friend of hers probably has something to tell us.
Have you met that person?
I have.
But back then,
I was already convinced that Lee Dae Chul was the killer,
so I interviewed the person just for formality's sake.
I have a feeling that we're off to a great start.
Are you being sarcastic?
This case is like a blank piece of paper.
To completely rewrite the story, it's better this way.
You have such a way with words.
CIVIL COMPLAINTS COUNSELING OFFICE
Why was this on your desk, Detective Kwon?
There are two possibilities here.
You either kept this intentionally...
or simply forgot to submit this piece of evidence...
to the evidence room.
I suppose we'll have to look further into this matter,
but I believe that the latter is right.
Initially, our main target was Detective Kang Do Chang.
However, we still have a long way to go...
to prove that he is indeed guilty of corruption.
I'd appreciate your help, Detective Kwon.
So you're saying...
I'm not asking you to make up something that never happened.
Just tell me what Detective Kang is up to.
I just want the truth.
All you need to do is keep me in the loop.
EVIDENCE
As for the conclusion on how this ended up...
in your hands, I'll wait to receive information that can satisfy me.
From what I remember, you and the late Ms. Yoon Ji Sun...
shared this studio for three years. Right?
Yes.
Then you probably know all the people...
who she spent the most time with. Her boyfriend, for example.
The thing is, Ji Sun was an introvert.
She rarely talked about herself to others.
I don't know any of her friends other than those in our department.
What did she usually draw?
She drew a lot of portraits.
Did she ever tell you about drawing a portrait of her boyfriend?
She might have drawn one for her boyfriend.
No, she always hired models for her portraits.
She refused even when her friends asked her to draw their portraits.
She was very proud of her oeuvre.
Then do you remember anyone among those whom she hired...
as her models?
Around the time of the murder.
Gosh.
I'm not sure. It was too long ago.
Please try to remember.
Mr. Oh will be here right after the meeting.
What kind of tea would you like?
Please don't worry about it.
Hey.
Get down. There's no one here.
Gosh.
Hey.
You shouldn't underestimate Oh Jong Tae.
If we mess with him,
the higher-ups might pressure us even more.
You're sure that Oh Jong Tae is linked to the case, right?
Speaking with him will give us a better idea.
There was something she was working on leading up to the incident.
But I don't know who the model was.
Ji Sun never showed me the portraits she was commissioned to draw.
In some cases, her clients asked her to keep it confidential.
Who were her clients that commissioned her?
Rich people, of course. Those with a lot of egos.
Are there any of her portraits still lying around here?
Well, I'm not sure. I think her parents took most of them.
Just a moment, please.
Well...
I don't think any of her finished work is here,
but some of her sketches might still be here.
She always did sketches like these...
prior to using paint.
But these just show the outlines of the silhouettes,
so you won't be able...
to recognize the models from these sketches.
So you think this portrait was done by the late Yoon Ji Sun?
Is there a signature or anything like that at the bottom?
I'm sure she didn't sign it.
She was ashamed of...
being paid to draw these as a side gig.
But all things aside,
a normal person...
wouldn't want to hang a portrait drawn by the woman...
whom he killed...
in his own office. Am I wrong?
That guy doesn't care about things like that.
What? Do you know him?
I see you often these days.
What brings you here today?
SPECIAL THANKS TO PARK JI HWAN AND LEE HYUN WOOK
Sub by ®VIU
The Good Detective - JTBC
Synced by ParkMinYoung℠
THE GOOD DETECTIVE
I received a tip that Oh Jong Tae was dating Yoon Ji Sun at the time.
She was very pretty.
There's something I fear.
Not catching the culprit.
There's a culprit I must catch no matter what.
Did you kill her?
Why did you arrest Jo Seong Dae?
For killing Park Gun Ho.
- You scumbag.
- What's your problem, you jerk?
There's someone who may be innocent.
- Eun Hye.
- Are you confident?
I'm confident that I can prove it,
and I can handle the consequences.
I deceived you.
I actually killed someone.
We're not trying to catch the culprit.
We're trying to save a life.
Sir.
Please save my dad.