♪ Listen, baby ♪
♪ Ain't no mountain high
Ain't no valley low ♪
♪ Ain't no river wide enough
Baby ♪
♪ If you need me call me ♪
♪ No matter where you are
No matter how far ♪
♪ Don't worry, baby ♪
♪ Just call my name
I'll be there in a hurry ♪
♪ You don't have to worry ♪
♪ 'Cause baby there ♪
♪ Ain't no mountain
High enough ♪
♪ Ain't no valley low enough ♪
♪ Ain't no river wide enough ♪
Kitchen's closing
in a minute, folks.
Can I get you anything else?
-Um, banana split, please.
-I'll try the banana split.
Ha! Cute.
Coming right up, both of you.
-Hi.
Night owl, huh?
Not usually. I just...
I have lots of paperwork
to finish tonight.
All right. Yeah. I thought
part of being a grownup meant
no more homework. Right?
Yeah. Just selling
my mom's house.
Oh. Yeah, I just... Did she...
-I mean, uh--
-She passed away
a few years ago.
It's been
kind of hard to let go.
-I'm sorry.
-Thanks.
You live here?
Um... I live in California now,
but I grew up
just a few blocks from here.
You?
Oh, I've lived in
a lot of places,
but I live
in California now, too.
- Van Nuys, right there
in Los Angeles.
Me and my boy.
Valley Village.
I'm Barbara, by the way.
Pardon me. Pat.
-Pat? Hi.
-Hi.
So what brings you out here?
Well, I'm just kind of
passing through.
I'm on a hunt.
Or a...
I collect old cars.
-Oh, wow.
-Yeah.
Would you believe it,
we only have one banana left.
Fred used most of 'em
in the pies.
I'm fine. You take it.
Thank you.
I have a better idea.
♪ Who wrote the book of love ♪
♪ Tell me, tell me, tell me ♪
It's pretty good.
♪ Was it someone from above ♪
♪ I wonder, wonder who
Mmbadoo-ooh, who ♪
♪ Who wrote the book of love ♪
♪ I love you darlin' ♪
♪ Baby, you know I do ♪
♪ But I've got to see
this book of love ♪
♪ Ours is the one that's true ♪
♪ Who wrote the Book of Love ♪
What?
- What the hell is going on?
What is that thing?
- Okay.
I realize that's gotta look
pretty darn weird,
Barbara, but--
Oh! That...
-Okay.
-That's a broom.
From Sharper Image.
No. I'm telling her
the truth, Court.
Right now.
Fine. It's not a broom.
-It belonged to Starman.
-It's Dad's.
What?
Would you please just
let me do the explaining--
Dad was a superhero,
and now I'm a superhero, too.
Okay. Hey, don't lead
with that.
-What that is--
-Jordan Mahkent killed Dad.
What is she talking about?
All right. Just...
Let me start at the beginning.
Stripesy?
- You?
- Hmm.
It was a long time ago.
He goes by STRIPE now.
Oh, now? You go by STRIPE now?
Occasionally.
And Jordan Mahkent...
Mom, listen.
Jordan, my boss,
is the iceman.
Icicle.
And he's behind everything bad
going on in Blue Valley.
He killed Dad.
Your dad, who was Starman?
Are you crazy?
-Filling my kid's head
with this nonsense?
-Mom!
Telling her that her father
was a superhero?
That Blue Valley's some hideout
for a supervillain gang?
Barbara, I realize
it doesn't make sense
unless you know all the facts--
Pat didn't do anything.
-The Staff chose me.
-Courtney,
-go upstairs.
-Being the Stargirl
is my birthright.
Starman is not your father.
I know he told you his name
was Sam Kurtis,
but that was just an alias.
This is my dad.
Sylvester Pemberton.
Starman. He was a member
of the Justice Society.
And the reason
he didn't show up
on Christmas--
No, enough!
The proof is right here.
Do not touch that thing.
But, Mom, it--
Will you just go to your room,
right now!
Look. I realize
that this is a lot to process.
If this lunacy of you being
an assistant superhero--
Sidekick.
I was a sidekick.
If this is remotely true...
then our whole marriage
is a lie.
That's not true, Barb.
Everything we are together
is real.
This family is real.
You dragged my daughter
into this insanity.
You told her that her father
was Starman.
I wanted this stuff
to stay in the past!
None of this
was supposed to happen!
Tell me one thing, Pat.
One true thing.
When Courtney was hurt,
and you took her
to the hospital...
was that really
from a car accident?
No.
You need to go.
-Barbara--
-Get out of this house.
Dad.
I remember.
It was last month,
I remember you
blowing out six candles.
Where have
the last ten years gone?
How could I forget ten years?
-I don't know.
-My memory...
It will come back.
It has to.
Why are we here?
You had a seizure.
No. I mean...
in Nebraska?
You moved us here
after Mom died.
Merri?
She's...
You don't remember?
A long time ago, um...
there was an accident.
She drowned.
I see.
She was supposed to pick me up
from school that day.
And I was scared that
she had forgotten about me.
You said you found her
in the pool.
You said that she was ice cold.
I loved her.
Can you hear me, Dad?
Junior?
You have my gift?
Did I know this?
Was I teaching you?
No.
It started when you were
in a coma.
I may have been
trying to reach out,
triggering your
latent abilities.
I know...
how frightening
these powers can be
when they first develop.
I'm going to help you, son.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
Dad, wait!
Is everything okay with Barb?
I heard her. She sounded upset.
I can't explain it right now,
okay, Mike, but, um...
I'm gonna go spend the night
at the garage.
Just, uh,
get a good night sleep.
All right? And I'll be back
in the morning.
And then what?
Well, Mike...
Uh...
I don't know, Mike.
Wait, uh... Are you guys
gonna get a divorce?
I hope not.
I'll come with you.
-No, it's okay.
-Come on. You're my dad.
I'll come with you.
Okay. Yeah.
Thanks.
And you know, Mike...
I don't know if I
tell you this enough, but--
Don't get all shaky
on me, big guy.
I'm gonna go pack a bag.
Well...
I love you.
Merri...
No!
Merri!
Last day...
I loved her...
Drowned... My wife... Last day
So beautiful...
Last day, Jordan, Icicle, Starman...
Dad...
Henry.
It's good to see you,
old friend.
My wife is dead.
Just like that.
Merri's...
gone.
I guess I never talked much
about her, did I?
We met while I was
robbing a bank.
A bank, of all things.
Such a cliche.
"Merri... The Girl
of 1,000 Gimmicks,"
the papers called her.
And me, the terrible telepath,
"Brainwave."
I was stunned by her thoughts.
They were so... pure.
So good.
So different
than everyone else's,
it gave me pause.
And she caught me.
In more ways than one.
Seeing the world
through Merri's eyes
made me question Jordan
and his mission.
But Jordan couldn't allow that.
He led the Justice Society
of America to us.
And we killed them.
Including Merri's brother...
Starman.
Starman?
I knew she would
never forgive me
for playing a part in it.
I hoped she would go
into hiding.
But she didn't.
Damn you, Jordan.
There are no more
good thoughts to be found.
Merri is dead.
Jordan.
We can't go out right now.
My mom's already too upset.
Go back to your crate.
It's taken
the better part of a decade,
but Project: New America
is finally on the precipice
of becoming a reality.
Dr. Ito's machine
is near completion.
All it needs now is you.
Your power,
and we can take control
of every poisoned mind
in six states.
We'll carve out
the heart of America,
and we'll control it.
Can you imagine, Henry?
Reshaping that many thoughts?
Helping them to see the light.
Our light.
Our way.
What about this "Stargirl"?
The one that put me here?
Who is she?
You're not much without
your master, are you?
I'm so curious.
When did you come from?
Is that Starman's staff?
Come with me, Henry.
All your questions
will be answered.
Dr. Ito will help you remember.
What is it?
Nothing.
Where's the Staff?
It's not downstairs!
Well, hopefully, Pat took it.
Mom, that Staff
might be the only thing
that can stop Icicle!
And I'm the only one
who can use it!
We're leaving.
Leaving?
I have been up all night.
And I don't know what is true
or what's a lie,
but I know I don't want you
anywhere near Blue Valley.
Or Pat.
Mom, please.
If you'd understand,
he was only trying to help me
get justice for Dad!
Starman was not your father.
You're wrong.
I'm going to work.
Mom, you can't go to work.
Jordan Mahkent is there,
and he killed Dad
and a lot of other people!
So start packing.
I'll be back in an hour.
-Is my staff in there?
-No.
It's not in its crate.
It came to me last night,
and I said
I couldn't go out, and...
Where could it have gone?
I don't know.
We have to find it, and we have
to take the fight to Jordan.
Mom wants
to leave Blue Valley today.
Today?
Yeah. She went to the office
to go get her things
and told me to pack up.
I gotta get her out of there.
I told her not to go, but...
-What should I do now?
-Just...
-Listen to your mom.
Go home and pack. Okay?
-But--
-No, Courtney.
-Pat...
That's it. It's over.
It's my fault.
Losing your mother,
that'll hurt forever,
all right?
But I can live with it
as long as I know
you're both safe.
Pat...
Hey.
Can you tell me
what's really going on?
I'm sorry, Mike. I...
I can't tell you.
You really never wanted me
and my dad around, did you?
That's not true.
Brothers and sisters
trust each other.
They tell each other
everything.
They help each other.
I know they do, but--
But you're not my sister.
I get it.
Have a good life, Court.
Mike, no! Mike!
It's all right.
Okay.
Courtney!
Henry?
I have so much to say,
and I don't know
where to start.
We killed them.
Including Merri's brother,
Starman.
Damn you, Jordan.
Merri is dead.
Look... I'm sorry!
Stay away from me!
Look! I don't know
what that was.
I could see everything
you were thinking.
Your dad's awake?
Wait!
And your mom was...
Starman's sister?
Yeah.
You're my cousin?
We're family.
Uh, we...
We can sort this out
later, right?
Yeah.
Jordan has your staff.
And my dad.
Henry, your dad knows who I am.
He said he was going
to kill my mom.
He can't remember anything
from the last ten years.
What?
He doesn't remember anything
since the day my mother died.
I think it hurts him too much.
That's good. I mean... sad.
But right now, good.
I need to get my staff back.
And I need to save my dad.
He's different.
I think my mom
was starting to change him.
I saw it.
I felt it.
I bet that's why
Jordan killed her.
He killed your mom and my dad.
We are going to need help, too.
Come on.
Way to go, Court.
You've just given away
our identities to the enemy.
Henry's not the enemy.
Yes, he is.
Look, if it helps,
she didn't tell me anything.
I read her mind.
Which he's not going
to do anymore.
That's only polite.
Listen...
my mom wants me and her
to leave town today. Forever.
No. You can't go.
I know.
But if we find the staff
and are able to stop the ISA,
maybe we can all
only save the town,
but we can also save
Pat and my mom.
And save this asshole's dad?
Courtney.
If Brainwave gets
his memories back,
he'll kill you first,
but then we're next.
He'll figure out
all of our identities,
unless Junior here
gives us up first.
I'm not telling anybody
anything.
We all know
if we find Brainwave,
we should break him in two
while we can.
You're not gonna hurt my dad.
Yeah? Try and stop me.
Rick.
How 'bout you try... right now?
Sit down.
Stand up.
No worries. Just ignore us
like you usually do.
I told you to stay away,
to not touch my friends.
You know what I'll do to you.
Hey! Save it for the bad guys.
Henry is the bad guy, Court.
No way I'm working with him.
What about Pat?
What's Pat think of all this?
I think he's
with my mom.
She was so mad.
We need to do this, everyone.
For Court.
The only reason
I'm agreeing to do this
is because I know
you'll do it anyway,
and you need someone
to watch your back.
You chose Henry over me,
after all he did.
We're not friends anymore.
You can't be here.
This is literally the most
dangerous place in town.
Hey! You said
you were leaving Blue Valley.
Why are you bothering
with this?
Because Jordan,
and then Sam,
and then Starman.
And I don't know
what to think right now.
This isn't a mystery
that you need to solve, okay?
Just get Courtney
and go far away. All right?
Oh. Hi, Pat.
- Hello, Barbara.
- Hi.
Don't you look lovely today.
Thank you, Sofus.
Uh, it's nice
to see you here, Pat.
Good to see you, too.
Pat's still not answering.
Should we wait for him?
We can't.
I just hope
him and my mom are okay.
So... who wants to go first?
Sorry, I've already been
down here before.
Scary.
Come on.
Chuck?
My goggles kind of still work.
I mean, I can see,
but Chuck keeps cutting out.
So no info from Chuck
and no Cosmic Staff.
Great.
What now?
We split up, I guess.
You'd always say
stick together.
We don't have a choice
right now.
Yolanda, Rick,
and Beth, go one way.
Henry and I will go the other.
Oh, I'm not leaving you
alone with him.
No. I'm coming with you.
Fine. Us three
will go this way,
Rick and Beth go that way.
We do some recon
and meet back here
in 15 minutes.
Got it.
It's to thank you.
For dinner.
That is so thoughtful.
Okay. We have some
family business
to take care of,
but it's good seeing you both.
-Have a nice day.
-Tell those children hello.
- We will.
- Okay, bye.
Bye, Jordan.
What?
Do you speak Norwegian?
Me either.
I wish you could read my mind.
Why would I want to do that?
I know how much I hurt you.
And I'd honestly do anything
to take it back.
Well, you can't.
This place
goes on forever.
It's gotta lead somewhere.
What was that?
Let's see.
Rick!
What's in there?
That's Solomon Grundy.
That's the thing
that killed my parents.
My dad's close.
I can feel it.
Daddy!
Daddy, Daddy, Daddy, she's here!
That bitch is here!
Let me out!
Come on!
I wanna kill here, please?
Please, let me!
Please! Now!
Go.
What are you doing?
I'm going to rip this door off
and kill that thing.
Thought it was obvious.
No, Rick! That's not
why we're here.
Yeah. Change of plans.
Dad!
Henry?
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
I wanna kill her!
Please, please, please, let me!
No, no, no, Daddy!
Stargirl.
Daddy, Daddy, no!
Snapdragon.
Dragon King.
Come on, come on!
It's going to be okay. Come on.
No, Henry.
They already got to you.
They changed you back.
Changed me back?
This is who I am.
Who I've always been.
It's who you are, too.
No!
It's too late. Let's go.
Please, Rick!
We have to go.
This isn't why we're down here!
Stop!
The others are counting on us!
Rick, who are they?
Who are they?
We should go. We should go!
I'll be back.
We've got company.
Us too. Come on!
I can't believe
you recorded them.
I wanted answers I could trust.
I realized I had
to find them myself.
I just meant you thinking
to tape the Mahkents,
that was a great idea.
I wouldn't have
thought of that.
It was good thinking.
I like her.
You can see
how Jordan looks at her.
It won't matter soon.
Once the machine is turned on,
everything will change.
What machine?
What are they planning?
-Pat?
-I don't know.
Barbara?
I got this.
Here, Beth! Go!
Come on!
Courtney, come on!
Settle down, children.
You can't hide from me.
How about an assist?
Move it.
Courtney, come on! Let's go!
You first.
Chuck! Can you hear me?
You're misdirected,
but you're strong, Henry.
That's good.
Stand back!
Dad...
listen to me...
I know what these powers
did to you.
How they warped
what you believed in.
But people aren't monsters.
I don't want to fight you.
I love you.
And I love you.
Let me train you.
The power, Henry,
you have no idea--
No.
You're better than this.
Mom knew you could be good.
She believed in you!
I know
you loved her.
And I know Jordan killed her
because she saw
the good in you, too.
Junior.
Jordan didn't kill your mother.
I did.
You?
I had to make a choice.
Don't make me
choose again, son.
Stand by my side now.
Or not at all.
I will never stand
by your side.
Good-bye, son.
Henry! No!
Chuck, come on. Come in.
Henry, get up!
I am sorry.
You're right.
People are good.
Don't let this change
your mind.
♪ Somebody said
You got a new friend ♪
♪ There's a big black sky
over my town ♪
♪ And yeah, I know
it's stupid ♪
♪ But I just gotta see
it for myself ♪
♪ And I'm giving it my all, ♪
♪ but I'm not the guy
you're taking home ♪
♪ But you don't see me
standing here ♪